Michael Stanton

Software Engineer



Manchester, UK+44 7916 925075

✓ M.S.Stanton@outlook.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/mokeaveli

Professional engineer with 2+ years' experience in software engineering. Passionate about driving positive change through computing applications. Able to draw upon a broad technical skillset, and solid understanding of computer science fundamentals to effect decision making and influence local strategy. Accustomed to transnational teamwork, in a highly regulated environment focused on delivering value on-time and in budget whilst remaining mindful of the voice of the customer. Ambitious, self-motivated, and ready to embrace a new challenge.

Proficiencies: Python, Java, Go, R, Git, SQL & C#

Key Skills: Reliability, Enthusiasm, Critical Thinking, Problem

Solving, Innovation

Experience

Software Engineer, Mobile & Edge Team / Couchbase

JAN 2024 - PRESENT

Joined the Couchbase Lite team with a focus on Mobile Vector Search. Collaborated with the project lead to design, implement, and test Vector Search for mobile and edge applications. Conducted several company-wide presentations to demonstrate the new feature and gather feedback. Engaged in cross-platform mobile development using Android, Java, C# .NET, and C.

Software Engineer, Cloud Native Team/Couchbase

JULY 2022 - JAN 2024

Software engineer in the Cloud-Native team at Couchbase, specializing in NoSQL distributed database solutions. Developed and maintained the Couchbase Autonomous Operator within Kubernetes to manage Couchbase Server resources. Implemented CI/CD infrastructure resulting in a 50% reduction in release time and cloud testing costs using Golang and Python.

Data Analyst Intern/Get Safe Online

SEP 2021 – FEB 2022

In-situ Data Analyst for major safeguarding consultancy firm, focussed on identifying trends in cyber-crime affecting young people. Opportunity to shadow senior data analyst and apply R-programming skills developed at university. Accustomed to rigors of changing business environment, providing daily reports to Agile Product Owner whilst influencing the company deliverable based on current trends and perceived vulnerabilities.

Education

Computer Science (BSc)/Lancaster University

SEP 2018 – SEP 2021

Compounded a passion for computing with world-class education to achieve a first-class honours degree in Computer Science. Wide range of modules completed encompassing the foundations of computer science and data analytics —including programming, software engineering, and artificial intelligence. Dissertation involved developing a neural network to tackle and overcome a real-world problem by classifying actions from skeletal input data in python3 using TensorFlow2. Applied learning in creation of Optimal Control Model for epidemiology of SARS-CoV using R, and further explored data clustering/classification for use in machine learning models in Python.

Qualifications

2018 – 2021: BSc in Computer Science (1:1 Honours) – Lancaster University

2016 – 2018: A-Levels in Mathematics, Further Mathematics & Computing (Grade A, B, A)

2011 – 2016: 12 GCSEs Grade A*-C, including A* in Mathematics, Science and English

Competencies

- Agile Project Experience
- Big-Data Analytics
- Neural Network System Architecture Design in TensorFlow
- R Studio for Data Analytics
- Cloud Computing Experience in Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Azure
- CI/CD Fundamentals using *Jenkins*
- Programming Proficiencies:
 - → Python, Java, Go, R, MATLAB, Git, MySQL

Accreditations

- Associate Member of BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT
- Lancaster University 2020 Hackathon Finalist
- Lancaster Masters Scholarship Recipient
- STEM Ambassador
- GetSafeOnline Key Stage 2 Educator

Interests

Personal Development • Sport & exercise science • Sustainable agriculture • Yoga • Strategy Games

References

[Available upon request]

Website:

To stay informed with my latest projects, and for a demonstration of previous work, please head to:

Mokeaveli.com